mail: bruno.baere@gmail.com phone: +5521996826336

SUMMARY

I am motivated by challenging tasks and to teach others about what I have learned. My experience as both an academic researcher and as a systems analyst helps me to approach, to model, to understand problems, and to develop a solution. My analytical skills have been proven useful in detecting and preventing bugs and problems in systems modeling.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Systems Analyst

Feb 2020 - Present

Instituto Tecgraf - PUC-Rio, Computational Geophysics Group

C++ developer in v3o2 project. Development and support of the software using modern C++.

Product Owner Feb 2018 - Jan 2020

Instituto Tecgraf – PUC-Rio, Computational Geophysics Group

Product Owner in v3o2 project. Responsible for the product value of various parts of the software dealing with geology and geophysics. Responsibilities included: understand the client needs, propose a solution, create user stories for the development team, and manage client expectations. I also wrote and maintained the product manual for the parts I was responsible for, and helped restructuring the recruitment interview process.

Senior Systems Analyst / Researcher

Aug 2011 - Feb 2018

Instituto Tecgraf - PUC-Rio, Computational Geophysics Group

C++ developer in v3o2 project, a seismic and well data visualizer for Petrobras running on RedHat/CentOS 5 using OpenGL, GTK+, boost, and Qt. For QA used GoogleTest framework, valgrind, and cppcheck. I organized and wrote the documentation of the development environment setup for home office, and worked on the upgrade to RedHat/CentOS 6. I also presented with colleagues a 2 day workshop on Scrum for team members.

Researcher

Apr 2009 - Aug 2011

ICAD/Visionlab - PUC-Rio

Researcher in games, digital entertainment and simulations. C# programmer in a joint project with CENPES and USP. Developed a shade tree editor in C# and Windows GDI for building DirectX shaders for the proof tank visualizer project.

Undergraduate teaching assistant

Mar 2009 - Dec 2009

Department of Computer Science – PUC-Rio

Worked as UTA for Introduction to Programming (C language) and Data Structures. Gave extra classes at Saturdays and post-class hours, resolving exercises and exams.

Intern

Oct 2008 - Mar 2009

ICA - Laboratório de Inteligência Computacional Aplicada – PUC-Rio

C# developer. Worked at FxANEEL project, developing part of the user interface with WindowsForms and XML. Developed a wrapper for GSLIB library in C# and created the model for library documentation used by the lab.

Scientific Initiation ICAD/Visionlab – PUC-Rio

Aug 2006 - Aug 2008

Development of a simulation library for Torque Game Engine. Researched game engine use in fluid simulations, programmed in C++ using OGRE rendering engine. Granted 2 years of CNPQ scholarship.

PUBLICATIONS

Maria das G. de A. Chagas, **Bruno B. P. L. de Araujo**, Waldecir V. Faria, Cezar G. Loureiro, Maria I. M. M. Carmo, Nelson J. Donato, Tathiana S. T. Silva, Victoria D. Maidantchik, Yann L. M. de M. Marques. *Design de Jogos de RPG Digitais: Uma investigação sobre a experiência de jogo*. In: Proceedings of XIV Brazilian Symposium on Games and Digital Entertainment (SBGames 2015), Teresina, Piauí, Brazil, November 2015.

Paula C. Ribeiro, **Bruno B. P. L. de Araujo**, Alberto Raposo. *ComFiM: A Cooperative Serious Game to Encourage the Development of Communicative Skills between Children with Autism*. In: Proceedings of the XIII Brazilian Symposium on Computer Games and Digital Entertainment (SBGames 2014), Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil, November 2014. DOI: 10.1109/SBGAMES.2014.19

Bruno B. P. L. de Araujo, Bruno Feijó. *Evaluating dynamic difficulty adaptivity in shoot'em up games*. In: Proceedings of the XII Brazilian Symposium on Computer Games and Digital Entertainment (SBGames 2013), São Paulo, Brazil, October 2013.

EDUCATION

M.Sc. in Computer Science, Computer Graphics

2010 - 2012

Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio de Janeiro - PUC-Rio

Advisor: Bruno Feijó

Dissertation title: A study on dynamic difficulty adaptivity for shoot'em up games

Granted 2 years of CAPES scholarship

GPA/CR: 3.54 (4.0 scale) / 89%

B.Sc. in Computer Engineering

2005 - 2009

Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio de Janeiro – PUC-Rio

Minor: Advanced studies in Mathematics

Final project title: A shade tree editor for OGRE materials

Granted 2 years of CNPQ scholarship

Language proficiency: Cambridge English FCE grade B2

2003

EXTRA-CURRICULAR COURSES

Data Science Math Skills	2021
Duke University on Coursera, 13h.	

Digital Product Management: Modern Fundamentals	2020
University of Virginia on Coursera, 16h.	

Fundamentals of Project Planning and Management	2018
University of Virginia on Coursera, 8h.	

O setor de games no Brasil: panorama, carreiras e oportunidades	2018
Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul, 30h.	

Introduction to User Experience Design	2017
,	2017
Georgia Institute of Technology on Coursera, 10h.	

	Gamification 2016 University of Pennsylvania on Coursera, 48h.
	A complexidade sensível: Um paralelo entre videogames e arte Universidade Estadual de Campinas on Coursera, 14h.
	Oil & Gas Industry Operations and Markets Duke University on Coursera, 10h.
	Geologia do petróleo para não-geólogos 2014 ABGP - Associação Brasileira de Geólogos do Petróleo, 20h.
CERTIFICATIONS	Certified Scrum Product Owner Valid: Mar 2014 - Mar 2022 Certifier: Scrum Alliance License: 000304959
	Certified Scrum Master Certifier: Scrum Alliance License: 000304959 Valid: Jan 2014 - Mar 2022
EXTRA- CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES	Co-organizer of PUC-Rio's Global Game Jam Helped organize PUC-Rio's Global Game Jam. Jan 2018, Jan 2020
AOIIVIIILO	Volunteer reviewer for Entertainment Computing 2016 - Present Volunteer reviewer for Entertainment Computing, an Elsevier journal. ISSN 1875-9521.
	Researcher at PUC-Rio's Game Design Research Group 2013 - Present Associate researcher in the Arts & Design Department research group under prof. Maria das Graças Chagas advisory. Themes include player-NPC relationship and artificial intelligence.
	SBGames 2011's Independent Games Festival contestant 2011 Contestant with the game Lights Out. Awarded with the third place in people's choice in the Art Game cathegory.
GAMES	Lights Out A puzzle-like art game for 2 players made in GameMaker 8.1. Presented at SBGames 2011, FILE Games 2012, Festival Games Brasil 2013. Role: programmer (GameMaker Scripting Language) and 2D artist.
	Seu Espião Safado! 2011 A print-and-play dice game for 3 players where 2 agents are trying to uncover a spy's secret (Brazilian Portuguese only). Role: game designer.
	You Are Trash! 2009 A Java 2D game mix of puzzle and platformer, made in the Gamerama project. Role: programmer and game designer.

RPG

Encontros Aleatórios: O Bando da Pena Vermelha, In: Forbidden Magazine #12, Buró Brasil, 2021. Link

Encontros Aleatórios: A Estalagem Lebre Confortável, In: Forbidden Magazine #9, Buró Brasil, 2021. Link

Ser Mago pra Quê?, In: Forbidden Magazine #4, Buró Brasil, 2020. Link

Zen e a Arte de Armadilhas, In: Forbidden Magazine #2, Buró Brasil, 2020. Link

Delírios de X'agyg: Episódio 1 - A Balada de Baleem Altrafer, Editor: Rafael Beltrame, RedBox Editora, 2017. Link

OTHER INFORMATION

Personal homepage: http://killerasus.github.io

GitHub: https://github.com/killerasus

Lattes curriculum: http://lattes.cnpq.br/0738342776987656